But the AI thematic side or the the
factor side, the vol is up towards 100.
Bitcoin vol is still at 30. So, if
you're putting an asset in a portfolio,
right now you can have three times as
much uh Bitcoin on a vol adjusted basis
as you can AI. And that means that we're
at a point where I think you should
start seeing more and more people as
they get more focused on Ethereum uh get
in. Once we get above the 200-day moving
average, I believe we're at the start
[music] of something new.
>> What's going on, guys? Today, we got a
great conversation with Jordie Visser.
In this conversation, we talk about all
of the deleveraging happening in the
stock market, why the mid-cycle slowdown
in AI may be impacting your portfolio.
We also get into what's going on with
inflation and Kevin Warsh's recent
comments. And then, last but not least,
we go and we cover what's happening with
Bitcoin, Ethereum, and the entire crypto
industry. Here's my latest conversation
with Jordie Visser.
All right, Jordie, I thought we could
start the conversation. It seems like
there's a big unwind happening in the
public market, specifically around a lot
of the AI names. You started talking
quite a bit about uh this like summer
slowdown and how that may affect things.
What what are you seeing?
>> Yeah, it's it's
uh
this is probably going to be uh a fairly
high-level um discussion. I'm going to
get a little wonky with the leverage
side, but
I think
um
people are going to have to get used to
this. So, what's happening is
the S&P is making new all-time highs or
equal weight S&P is making new all-time
highs.
Breadth is making new all-time highs.
The AI names are going down, so a lot of
people are sitting there seeing their
Micron go down and their Marvell go down
and their go through the list of all of
the names. Every single name,
Caterpillar, Modine, everyone that's
been
let's say going up fairly fast
is giving back some of that. Now, some
of that is related to just what I talked
about, which is the AI mid-cycle
slowdown is a second derivative change,
and Nvidia went through this back in
2024. And I highly recommend everyone go
back and look, because from chat GPT to
about June of '24,
Nvidia went up 12 times.
So, very similar to let's say Micron
going from 100 to 1,200.
Since that period in June of '24,
Nvidia's earnings have continued to
grow. They've continued to dominate the
AI trade, but in 2 years, they've now
gone up 48%.
Good returns. I mean, you're you're
getting 20-plus percent returns, you're
outperforming the S&P, but it's not the
12 times that happened. And that's where
we are in AI right now for all of these
names. Um meaning, most of them had
three to 10 times type moves, especially
the semiconductor names, which mean
they've built in a lot of the next 2
years. And I think what the market is
going through is this second derivative,
where when you look at the earnings of
these companies, you're like, "Oh my
god, they're up 400%, 500%." But then,
a year from now, they're only going to
be up
30%, 40%. So, you're decelerating. So,
that's the first part is I think the
market is coming to term with the AI
mid-cycle slowdown. And the other thing
I wrote about, which is the fireworks
show.
The The under-the-hood story is that
there is absolutely a deleveraging
happening. And I want to use, again,
a bunch of um comparisons. So,
silver and gold were up massively last
year.
Uh they had a drawdown the the biggest
drawdowns they've ever seen in 30 years
on different time horizons that were all
within 20 days.
The
momentum factor for technology has seen
an unprecedented move lower. I've posted
an X about it. And what that does is the
volatility rises, and whether it's a
single-name retail person that is taking
out leverage, whether it's Korean
investors whose margins accounts have
been closed or whether it's a long short
multi-strap market neutral hedge fund or
it's a systematic quant strategy. And
we've seen reports and numbers released
from the prime brokers of just very
large losses in a short amount of time.
And because the volatility has gone
higher, whether it's risk parity,
whether it's any kind of quant strategy,
when the volatility goes higher, you not
only have to reduce your risk at that
point just from volatility beginning,
but it also means that that position
when it starts to come back cannot be as
big. So, I think the best way for people
to understand this, this was going to
happen in a case like Micron by going
from 100 to 1200 and back down to 800 as
of early this morning,
you've given back now depending on the
name 30 to 50%. We've done enough based
on what I think is there and I think
we'll probably start to form some sort
of a bottom here.
But like silver, like gold, and another
one like Bitcoin after October 10th,
these things have not come back yet. So,
their vol may have come down, but those
things have been on the downside and
they haven't gone back. The difference
is with the AI trade, they were
significantly above their 200-day moving
average. And so, everyone hears this.
Many of these names like Micron, they
were unchanged for years. Micron was the
same price it at liberation day lows
that it was in 2017.
So, a lot of these were breaking out of
long-term ranges. They're way above
their 200-day moving average.
I think somewhere between this 30 and
60% retracement, they're going to hang
in there and they'll start to move
higher again.
But I think the fireworks show is over
and I think from this point on, some
names will do well, some names won't do
well, and you'll see volatility and
gradually come down, but not quickly and
not something that's going to just turn
into a oh, that was no problem. It was
something real and it's about leverage.
>> Do you have a framework for identifying
which are the ones that will do well and
which ones won't?
>> Well, what I'm going through and I I
wrote a paper about memory. I think
memory is the most important part of the
AI trade.
I am focused on companies that are have
not yet see their step up function in
earnings. So, in the case of Nvidia,
when it peaked in 2024 from a 12 bagger,
one thing started to happen, which is
they started to only beat earnings by a
little bit. So, the names that I'm
focused on are the ones that I still
think are going to beat earnings by a
significant amount quarters to come, not
just this quarter. Memory obviously blew
away numbers. So far, we've seen Micron
blow away numbers. We've seen Samsung
blow away numbers. We've seen ASML blow
away numbers.
And all the stocks traded lower.
So, the semiconductors are going to be
fine, but memory is the place that I'm
going to be focused on. And then I'm
writing a a very long piece, or I did
write it, which I'll release on my
paywall this weekend, about Vera Rubin.
And Vera Rubin is another area where
there's certain names in there which
haven't seen the step up function in
earnings yet. That is going to be the
things that drives it is you're going to
need to beat earnings significantly. And
if you're just beating them by a little
bit, you can still produce 25% a year
returns like Nvidia has, but you're not
going to get back up into the 60s and
70s. So, I think everyone's going to
have to now do some homework.
That's the reason why I have my 100 name
portfolio and I'll be spending the time
on which names are better than others.
>> Now, a lot of what has been driving the
AI trade has been all of these
bottlenecks. And a huge piece of the
bottleneck was that there was two major
American companies, maybe a third was
trying to enter the fray in terms of
Grok.
But, we just got the Kimmy K3 release.
And this is a Chinese open source model.
It seems to be performing as well, if
not better, than Fable or any of the
latest closed source American models.
Does that change any of your analysis if
all of a sudden the winning models or
these open-source models versus them
being the American closed-sourced?
>> No, and this is this is a good time to
to bring this up. Um
so I I wrote a paper this week on Brad
Gerstner's interview uh on well, it
wasn't an interview. He he was a guest
on the All-In pod.
And on that
every answer he gave on this to me was
very balanced. It kind of went through
the pros and cons of all these stories.
But the comment that I really focused on
the most, which I think people have to
understand
this is the largest TAM
that will ever exist, at least on planet
Earth. We'll see if the the TAM in space
will actually be something that happens,
but that TAM is about intelligence. And
intelligence will drive revenues that
will drive compute demand. So here's the
thing with open-source and and and with
the frontier models.
Right now, if I wanted to use Kimiko
3.0, I couldn't do it. Neither could
you, unless you had the hardware.
There's no way to use it. Meaning, could
an enterprise use it? Yeah. So it's
isolated right now to
people that have enough hardware to use
it. There's no way to even get the hard
You have to have GPUs to be able to run
it. Like this is a big model. That's the
only way it competes with the frontier.
If you want to use Anthropic, you just
go onto the cloud and you go use it. So
there is this element of well, who's
going to be the people that use it? Will
developers use it? Yeah, they probably
will. Um they're trying to reduce costs.
So AI-native businesses are going to
have a huge advantage. Will an
enterprise company in the United States
of America use a Chinese open-source
model?
Maybe over time. Um but they're trying
to get adoption from the humans plus the
agents. Humans need co-work. Humans need
all of these things and they get used to
using a model. So, you just can't keep
swapping out every time there's a new
model. It's not that easy. And so, I
think if they're, you know, if they're
going to bet on something from an
enterprise perspective, which is where
the revenue is being driven, I don't buy
into the fact that these Fortune 500
companies are going to all of a sudden
go, "You know what? I'm going to get rid
of Fable 5 and Anthropic and I'm going
to move to this Chinese model. We're
going to download it and we're going to
teach our employees how to use something
which doesn't have the tools. So, the
intelligence and the benchmarks may be
there, which is fine for someone who
knows how to code themselves and someone
who's an engineer, but it's not that
easy for the employees to actually go
through. So, I think people have to be
very careful about this. I hear this
repeatedly. And go back to Brad
Gerstner's side. This is the largest
individual TAM. Will people use open
source? 100%.
Will most of the token usage be open
open source? Yeah, it already is. But
what we've seen so far over the last 6
months, and they talked about this on
the All-In, the actual
enterprises are reducing their open
source and going more towards this
because that's the way their bureaucracy
and everything works. And I think people
have who haven't worked for a Fortune
500 company, which I have done,
>> [gasps]
>> the bureaucracy of getting decisions
made, how long it takes to decide on a
model, how long it takes to decide on
software, and then once you do, you have
a long-term plan. I don't see the
Fortune 500 companies in the United
States switching to a Chinese model
anytime soon.
>> So, there's two parts of this that I
think are are interesting. Um, and these
are just things that we're actively
trying to figure out at Silvian, so I'm
going to use that experience extrapolate
where I think a lot of these companies
are probably doing. The first is, um, we
recently built and released uh, in the
product a model router. So, the average
consumer that's using Silvian has no
clue that this is happening, but um,
they can think of uh each query
previously was going to kind of the
highest intelligence, which also is the
most expensive model to be able to go
compute it. Which is great when you ask
a really complex question, but if you
ask what is the date, we probably don't
need, you know, superhuman intelligence
to be able to go and answer that
question. And so the way the model
router works is basically it can use the
highest intelligence, most powerful
model for really complex things, but it
can direct queries to whether it's open
source or kind of, you know, lower cost,
lower compute uh intense uh models for
simpler questions. And what I find
interesting about the model router is
one, we already are seeing a positive
impact from it and it's, you know,
putting some questions over to the to
the uh less powerful model. What I don't
know and we're actively trying to figure
out how many models could you put into
the model router? Does it make sense to
do it with two or three? Would you do 20
or 30? And I saw Sierra, uh Bret
Taylor's uh company, I think that they
have a blog post from their engineers
where they have about 20 different
models. It doesn't mean that's the right
way to do it, but it does feel like in
in a weird way um I agree that the open
source model for the average employee is
not going to be the thing that they're
going to just, you know, put on their
computer and all of a sudden start
using. But I wonder if some of these
companies start to create this, you
know, harness and environment and the
tools, and then they basically just use
the models on the back end, and the end
user doesn't even know what they're
using. They just know that, hey, this is
faster, this is, you know, more
accurate. What do you think about that?
>> I think that's the way it'll go. Um I
don't think there's any question. I
think the barriers to doing it right now
are are hard. Um there will be companies
that make it easier. So you're getting
to the point of let's think of the
models as outsourced intelligence.
So let's just pretend like these are
people. And you're like, okay, so I have
access to these 20 people. Well, you're
going to pay the highest price for the
most sophisticated things. Where this
shows up
is that we're in the early stages, the
very early stages of
the Jevons paradox situation, where
adoption is still extremely low. And we
know that because there hasn't really
been any job losses for any of the
companies, and so far they just haven't
been hiring people. I think when we get
to that point, the downside to me, which
I've always thought, is when people
extrapolate Anthropic's ARR, and they're
like, it'll be a trillion dollar what
we're saying, which I agree with, and I
don't buy into, they're going to be
there. I believe AI will disrupt all
businesses because intelligence will be
commoditized. Now,
that is not going to hurt Anthropic in
terms of growing their ARR, but I have
believed, and I still believe, that
taking this pace, and just because they
did it the last 3 years, 10 times, 10
times, and they're on pace for 10 times
again to get to a hundred billion ARR.
People are extrapolating saying, well,
next year they'll be a trillion. And I
do think there's an element of Jevons
paradox, but what you're talking about,
and I think what people should see and
and get,
I don't think they're going to get to
those numbers. Do I think they could get
to 200 next year? Yeah. Well, that's a
doubling, that's not 10 times. So, with
everything in AI, I think what people
have to realize, what I said with Micron
and with all these places, I think it
goes with Anthropic as well. Eventually,
you reach a point where this was a surge
out of nowhere, but eventually
competition shows up. And you and I have
talked about this, and I've said it
before, and I'm saying it more actively
as time goes on.
Demis Hassabis wrote a piece on AGI.
Demis Hassabis is the person that I
think is the most level-headed of the
people who I also think wouldn't say
anything unless he was confident that we
were getting there. I think Dario
Amodei, I think Sam Altman, they run
businesses where they're talking about
it. Sundar Pichai, they Demis Hassabis
doesn't run Google. He has talked about
AGI since 2010 and forecasted that it
would be around 2030. So, he's right on
the number. Well, he's now convinced and
saying
the world is going to change over the
next 3 years. And what it means for
public companies and private companies
and any company that exists,
you don't know if your business will be
disrupted by AI, but the probability of
that happening rises every day that we
get closer to AGI. So, we've talked
about terminal value. We've talked about
how you can't view Adobe and Salesforce
past the next 3 years.
I think you're starting to get in that
with all companies, and especially with
AGI, it even hits the physical
companies, the energy companies, the
Microns, the stuff like that, 3 years
from now. So, I think that's all coming
and that gets us back to This is the
reason why I say Bitcoin is the only
thing that has a moat, which is what's
an asset that I don't have to worry
about it being disrupted by AI,
but I still have to invest. I think
every single asset is going to run
through a problem where AI is going to
run into its moat.
>> All right, boys. I need you to pay
attention and listen. Most of you don't
realize, after the age of 30,
testosterone drops about 1% a year. And
the bigger issue isn't just total
levels. There's a protein called SHBG.
Yeah, I'm in my science bag with that
[music] one. SHBG.
Then it actually binds your testosterone
and it locks it up. So, even if your
number looks fine, a lot of it isn't
doing anything for you. That's where
Mars men comes in. Mars men is designed
to fix that. Clinically [music] dosed
ingredients that help free up bound
testosterone and support natural
production, energy, and recovery. It
works with what your body already makes,
not against it. And the feedback that
they're getting is consistent. People
are reporting more energy throughout the
day, sharper focus, better gym recovery.
It's not one-time spike. [music] It's
just simply a higher floor. Now, this
product is made in the United States.
It's [music] third-party tested and it's
backed by a 90-day money-back guarantee.
For a limited time, our listeners can
get 50% off for life plus free shipping
and they'll get three free gifts, too.
You can go to men go to mars.com. Again,
that's men go to mars.com for 50% off
and three free gifts when you check out.
After you purchase, they will ask you
where you heard about them. Please
support our show and tell them our show
sent you. Again, men go to mars.com, go
check out your testosterone and fix it
if it's broke.
>> What I also find interesting about the
open-source models versus uh the
American closed-source models is
everyone is I I think excited about
open-source allowing you to self-host
and be able to actually use your data in
your environment without having to worry
about the zero data retention policies
or, you know, the big model labs going
to take your information and train their
model or eventually compete with you.
The downside, though, is a lot of what
we're seeing with Soviet and the Chinese
open-source models is it is not well
understood how some of the Eastern world
values are incorporated into the
weights. And so, one aspect that I think
is not a conversation really at all, but
will become a conversation is this idea
of like cultural weights. So, if you
think of finance maybe is the best
example, if you use the generalization
of America and the West is capitalist
and China and the East is more
socialist, well, you obviously want the
capitalist responses or that kind of
capitalist weights into the model if
you're in the West.
We [snorts] just don't know, right? It's
really hard. I don't see a lot of
research there yet, but I do think that
just as much as people are worried
about, you know, what is the Google
algorithm or what is the TikTok
algorithm feeding the people, this idea
of like these cultural weights is going
to become a huge part and it goes back
to your point about these large
companies. There's like a technical and
user experience barrier that they've got
to overcome, but then also, you know, if
you're I don't know, a customer service
uh uh
product and all of a sudden you start
sharing, you know, kind of cultural
values in response to customers,
companies are probably going to get
pretty uncomfortable very quickly. And
so just feels like it's not only
technical, there's also this other
element that um is very uh
not understood at the moment that we're
going to have to do a lot of work on.
>> Yeah, and this is why in the end I you
you left one thing out uh or I don't
know if it's intentional or you guys
haven't thought about it with Silvia,
but
there is no way that we know for sure
that if you host your own model on your
own computer
that you're safe from people having
information from you. And let me let me
let me let me make sure people
understand why.
Once you start going on the internet,
you're exposed. So if you have this
thing sitting someplace and it's
contained, but you're never accessing it
to the internet, we don't know what back
doors or things could be in any of these
models to get to get through. So I I've
I've heard people talk about it. I I
think the naive part is when people get
into this, "Well, I'm not exposed." If I
use Chem I K 2.5, which I have on one of
my hardware,
I'm not worried about it in the same way
only because I don't have any of my
important information on my business in
there.
But on me going into the internet or
anything like that, if I use agents and
they've got credit card information or
wallet information, I just don't think
we're there. So I everything that you
said, I think it leads back to the fact
that
it is very difficult for a US Fortune
500 company to not use US frontier
models and probably
Google, Amazon, Microsoft as the cloud
provider in some kind of
you know, uh
cyber related way that they can think
about things along with their own cyber.
And that's why I think the adoption will
continue to go.
Um the reason I said that on the AI
side, I'm not worried about where we are
and what stocks I want to I want to be
involved in. I said it last week, I'll
say it now, and I'm going to show it on
the weekend video.
We have barely entered the agentic
world, barely. Consumer agents are
coming. Right now, we're at enterprise
agents, and they're barely being used.
And that's why when you go back to Brad
Gerstner's line, this is the largest TAM
of intelligence that it could be. So, if
we knew that the number was $20
trillion, and that there were six model
companies,
they're all going to make money.
That like in the end, they're all going
to make money. So, getting worried
about, you know, will they make any
money? Will open-source take everything?
It's not going to work like that. It's
going to be spread out. There'll be lots
of different players. Jevons paradox is
in play. Compute demands are everywhere.
Everyone's going to get a little piece
of the pie. The question is, if you're
pricing this stuff really low, like the
Chinese models are, like Meta is,
do you have other ways to make money?
Meta's trying to get it through the
consumer agent side, through
advertising, through a bunch of things
within side their world. Apple's trying
to do this with the Gemini model, to get
Siri in, to get volume going that way on
the hardware side, as well as dominating
in in terms of the personal intelligence
side. Everyone's in a race to monetize
this. I think it's a big pie. I just
think the model providers are going to
have an uphill battle from here,
compared to the last 2 years.
>> Another thing that happened this week
that I think is having a big impact on
the market is obviously the inflation
report. It came in much cooler than I
think people were expecting.
Um we also got some comments from Warsh.
What was your take on the data, and then
his commentary afterwards?
>> Well, I I think the most important part,
um
you know, what you and I talked about
the last couple weeks, and I said
probably about 3 weeks ago that
one of the biggest surprises to me with
this whole thing in the Strait of Hormuz
is how people could literally be this
wrong on something they had studied for
I don't know, 20, 30 years. If this ever
got shot down and we took down 20% of
this, what would happen? And the fact
that not only did crude oil trade down,
and obviously we're trading back up now
with rekindling and bombing and
everything, but
the second you stop bombing, we have the
next ceasefire, what's going to the
crude? I can't imagine it doesn't go
straight back down. I mean, I I don't
fall for the trap again, especially when
inflation swaps this week actually went
down. So, 2-year inflation swaps as of
yesterday were actually lower than where
we started the week. So, we're at the
lows. So, I think when you go through
the inflation data, number one,
there's just no way to read it. Unless
this month was a fluke on the core
services side,
every single inflation data but one, PCE
core is the only one that's pointing
upward. Everything else, whether it's
median
inflation,
trimmed mean, whether it's the CPI core,
whether it's sticky inflation, or
whether it's trueflation, they've all
come down while the PCE core is at the
highs of the year. And so, I'm leaning
towards the fact that the inflation side
is a non-story for the rest of the year.
Now, that being said, with the change in
inflation, we reduced the Fed rate hike
significantly. And I've talked about how
I think this is a very big positive for
the debasement trade, very big positive
for crypto. We haven't seen it play out
yet. We've seen Bitcoin act much better
during a momentum unwind, which is not
normal. But what Warsh said again, he's
reiterated,
he Basically, the headline for me is
this is not a hawkish-dovish thing. This
is a reform thing.
He is fixated on a point that you, you
know, brought up at the beginning of the
year repeatedly, which is we can't trust
any data from the government. He
believes that the Fed has been very
backward-looking, which I know I agree
with. I think looking at anything at a
time of AI, you know, 6 months later
when the data gets revised for, you
know, a long time, how can that be the
types of things that you make
decisions on? So, I think his message to
everyone there is we're in a completely
different time, and I think that aligns
with AI. He has talked about the fact
that AI is very disruptive. He's a big
believer in AI. He's also a big believer
in digital assets, and I don't think
people should forget that. So, I think
monetary policy, the old traditional
way, is gone, and the most important
thing for people is we've now taken the
July rate hike to a 10% chance.
So, if you believe what the um
uh where the expectations are, which is
one rate hike before the end of the
year,
you're kind of saying he's going to
raise rates before the midterm
elections, and
if he was going to do it, I think July
would be the time. I don't see him doing
it in September, October.
>> One of the aspects to me that
um
fuels uh
like it has been exasperated
in my understanding of all of this. Last
Sunday, I went to the Jay-Z concert, and
while we were there, we walked around
and I interviewed a bunch of people,
which basically just meant I put a
microphone in their face and said, you
know, why is everything so expensive?
If you did knew nothing about economics,
you'd never seen a data point in your
life, you would think that every single
person is just completely unable to
afford anything. Groceries are too
expensive, gas is too expensive. We did
it the day after the news came out that
rent in New York City uh the median rent
just hit a brand new all-time high of
like 5,250
bucks or whatever, right?
At the same time,
they're at a concert where the tickets
are, you know, 500 bucks, 700 bucks,
whatever. So, like there's a little bit
of irony in people who are at this event
where the ticket prices are really high,
talking about everything so inexpensive.
So obviously they got money from
somewhere they know somebody who's got
money.
But the second aspect [clears throat] of
it was almost nobody was actually
referring to inflation. They were just
referring to the aggregate increase in
price over the last five or six years.
And so what I do wonder is, you know, is
there good news on the horizon? It's
just going to take a couple of years.
Well, that doesn't help politicians at
the midterm. But it does feel like so
much of the discontent the kind of
issues in the actual economy in terms of
people's perspective of their real life
experience. It's all aggregate price
increase. Almost none of it has to do
with, you know, the inflation that you
and I would think about in terms of the
difference between 3.5 or 3.9%.
>> Yeah, I so I've thought a lot about this
and and
here here's my uh
here's my take.
If something bad happens to you,
uh you know, you have a ski accident,
you hurt your knee, you get into a car
accident.
For the next five years,
that thing is pretty front and center in
your brain.
>> [clears throat]
>> Um
I believe what's happened is we can all
remember what things cost before COVID.
Like it's in our head. We remember what
the car we bought cost. So every day
someone has to just make a decision
because cars have a some type of
lifespan. You're like, "You know what?
I'm going to go buy I'm going to I'm
going to trade this one in and go buy a
new car." And
I mean, I've run into this recently
where I went to go see because I have a
Model S that I bought in 2021. Well,
they're they're stopping the Model S.
I'm actually using the full self-driving
now on my car and it's an old version. I
want the newest version.
The car the cost is up significantly
from when I bought it in 2021. So my
brain remembers what I paid on
something. And I think this is one of
the things with you with with us with
COVID, never does inflation go up that
much in that short amount of time. Not
in all of our lifetime. So, normally
when inflation goes higher, it's this
gradual process. When it happened in the
'70s, it was driven by oil prices, and
so oil went up, oil went down. This one
wasn't that. This was Here you go,
here's trillions of dollars, everything
went up in price. Every single thing
went up in price. And so, I think we all
remember when eggs didn't cost
$6, $7 a carton. We all remember when
XYZ didn't cost this. And I think it
takes a long time for that to wear off,
but I think when you add in the
polarization and the fact that people
need someone to blame for this, and the
fact that AI is standing in front of
them where they don't feel like their
job is ever safe the way it was, I
really think I'm I'm getting to the
point now I agree with you because
I grew up in a house where my
grandmother told me about the Great
Depression all the time, about not
having money for food, being thrown out
of her house in in her teens to
basically they couldn't afford She had
to go out and get a job. She had to go
do something. Um, and just remembering
what the Great Depression was, this is
not a We have the unemployment rate at
near all-time lows. You can borrow money
for anything right now. So, I I agree
with you that I think this is more of a
psychological inflation thing, and I
think it has a lot to do with just what
has happened in the last 5 years.
>> Given Warsh's comments, um, you know,
the first meeting that he really did a
press conference, he didn't say much.
Um, this was a little bit more robust in
in commentary. Uh,
do you change your mind at all about how
you're thinking about him as the leader
of the Central Bank or actions he may
take?
>> No, I actually
I think he's the right person for the
job because I do think the most
important thing for this current
Fed chair to be
is young enough
to understand the importance of AI,
which I don't think Jerome Powell had.
They didn't even pay attention to AI,
honestly, until like the fourth third,
fourth quarter of last year.
Um, at least from what they said
publicly. The second thing is, I think
it needs to be more of a market person
and less of an academic. And I think
that's another important part that, you
know, Warsh
worked at Morgan Stan- Like Warsh has a
background in capital markets in the
same way that Bessent does. So, you have
Bessent and him involved right now in
the market at a very important time. For
people not focused on digital assets,
and again,
th- this is you're going to be hearing
me talk about this a lot more. I mean,
our our lives are crossing over to a
very important point starting there
because,
you know, everything I'm starting to do
in my video is related to what's going
to happen for me in the second the final
four months of the year when I get out
of Maine.
I mean, I'm very focused on the rise of
agents and what Bessent and Warsh are
talking about, which is the importance
of the United States of America
being the leaders of the financial
guardrails, not losing the
the benefit that they admit has been a
huge benefit for the world, which is
reserve currency of the world, Swift,
all of these different things. Digital
assets are major part of it, and the
growth that's happening in prediction
markets, the growth that's happening in
real world assets and tokenization. The
news we saw this week on tokenization.
All of this stuff is happening, and so I
think Kevin Warsh is the right person at
a major inflection point that very few
people on Wall Street
that are on the hedge fund world are
fully embracing yet. I think they're
realizing they have to, and with AI now
being in a massive volatility spike, I
think now we're going to start to see
some money looking for new beta, and I
think that's where Kevin Warsh is going
to be a a big asset. So, I'm very happy
with the reform that's going to happen
on all these fronts related to AI.
>> The second that inflation starts to cool
and interest rate hike odds start to
come down, I think a lot of people look
at something like Bitcoin and try to
understand how is that reacting and and
what is that telling us about the
future. Seems like Bitcoin had a pretty
strong bid this week. Um what was your
read on that?
>> Yeah, I'm actually going to take it a
different direction. I don't I mean, I
know Bitcoin is is is more of your focal
point. Um Ethereum's had the big move.
Um
it's up as of yesterday's close or let's
say yes since it doesn't close. As of
yesterday's equity close,
uh it was up close to 20% month to date.
Um and just so people understand,
that would be if we finish the month
with 20% the largest month or the best
month since August of last year. Um
Ethereum has outperformed Bitcoin. It's
been the largest on a cross versus
Bitcoin since then. The reason I care so
much about Ethereum is because I do
believe if AI agents are coming, if
tokenization is coming, if all of these
things are happening, this is an energy
within side of the revenue side of
crypto
and we there's
there's no there's no way to get around
what's happening volume-wise. I think
the Stripe
bid for PayPal
was a big deal, too. I have my crypto 40
name equal weight basket, similar to my
AI thematic one, meant to deal with the
agentic world.
And PayPal was one of the names in it.
And so
number one, I was happy I've done my
homework and figured out which public
companies cuz there's six of them that
are in there including Robinhood,
how they all fit in with this crossover
with the AI agents. But I think Bitcoin
is just hanging in there very well on a
relative basis. It's obviously done well
versus um AI. But the AI thematic side
or the the factor side, the vol's up
towards 100. Bitcoin vol is still at 30.
So if you're putting an asset in a
portfolio right now, you can have three
times as much uh Bitcoin on a
vol-adjusted basis as you can AI. And
that means that we're at a point where I
think you should start seeing more and
more people as they get more focused on
Ethereum
getting. Once we get above the 200-day
moving average, I believe we're at the
start of something new. Until we are
above there, I'm trading it actively.
I'm trying to make sure that if a bottom
is made here,
it's there. I even put little started to
buy a little bit of Micron this week in
some of the semis. Micron, I have a
position again. It's very small relative
to what it was back then, and I'm buying
it at higher prices than where I ended
up selling it on average.
But that's because the new news that has
come out over the course of the last 6
weeks and the consolidation and the the
deleveraging that's happened,
I feel more confident in terms of
putting a little bit little bit of money
in there, but I'm still much more
heavily weighted towards crypto.
>> When you think of the crypto allocation,
is it just Bitcoin and Ethereum?
>> For me at this point, it's Bitcoin,
Ethereum, and and MicroStrategy. So I'm
not
I I'm I I don't think from
I'm sure this will change as I spend
more time in the space.
Uh
I've never been a big stock person as a
macro person. It's been thematic. So
even though Micron is in the portfolio,
if you ask me why, it's because of AI.
Everything I have in the portfolio to me
is either an AI trade or it's a crypto
trade. And so that's it. I I really Eli
Lilly, it's an AI trade.
Silver, it's an AI trade. Like anything
I have in the port- folio is related to
the stuff that I write about and I talk
about. I believe we are at the
convergence between AI and crypto and
that all public companies will be
disrupted the same way Adobe and
Salesforce have been. Same way the
hyperscalers have. They're they just
rallied off the bottom. That's why the
S&P's hanging around the all-time highs
while AI trades lower.
But over the last 9 months, they haven't
done anything. So again, when you go
through things, I'm just more focused on
the AI infrastructure trade. Once the
agentic side starts to accelerate, once
AGI gets here,
I believe the ROI C is headed towards
private companies. I believe small
private businesses are going to be the
winners of this. The enterprises will
find a way to reduce their expenses over
the next 2 years. We are seeing that
happen inside the public companies. If
you haven't seen it so far, about 40 of
the S&P 500 companies have reported so
far, and just like happened in Q1, the
surprise ratio right now, we're we're
outperforming earnings. It's been 16% in
terms of the beat.
Um so, we're again headed towards
another big, big, big month, uh big, big
quarter for earnings, and a lot of these
have happened in the banks and in
insurance companies.
>> Today's episode is brought to you by
Blofin. If you're actively trading
[music] crypto, then you already know
the platform matters. Execution speed
matters, liquidity matters, and
reliability during volatile markets,
that definitely matters. That's why more
traders are starting to use Blofin. They
built [music] a trading platform focused
on fast execution, deep liquidity,
advanced futures products, and a really,
[music] really clean user experience.
They don't overcomplicate things. You
can trade hundreds of spot and perpetual
pairs. They integrate directly with
TradingView, and they built the platform
for both active traders and people who
are just getting [music] started.
Security is a major focus, obviously.
Assets are custody with Fireblocks. They
provide proof of reserves, and they've
built a strong reputation for platform
stability during those high volatility
[music] environments. And to celebrate
the partnership with us, Blofin is now
giving away $100,000.
That's right. Blofin is going to give
away $100,000 in deposit and trading
rewards.
>> [music]
>> So, if you're looking for a better place
to trade crypto, go check them out today
using our link in the description.
Again, that's Blofin, the trading
platform built for serious [music]
crypto traders. Go sign up. Pay
attention, cuz they're giving away
$100,000 in deposit and trading [music]
rewards.
Today's episode is brought to you by
TikTok for Business. If you run a
company, you are probably already
spending a bunch of money on ads,
search, X, maybe meta. But there's a
platform your competitors are sleeping
on and the window to move first is
closing. TikTok has over 200 million
monthly active users in the US alone and
51% of that reach is unique, meaning
that those users aren't reachable on any
other major platform where you are
already buying. Unlike follower-based
platforms, TikTok's algorithm rewards
strong creative, not audience size. That
means a well-made video from a brand no
one's heard of can reach millions of
relevant users for companies trying to
acquire users cost-effectively, that's a
fundamentally different model. TikTok
for business gives you full-funnel tools
built for performance. Whether you're
looking to drive awareness, introduce
your products, or convert new audiences,
TikTok is becoming an important
discovery engine for businesses and
cryptocurrency alike. If you're a
founder, a CMO, or growth lead and you
haven't run a TikTok campaign yet, now's
the time to change that. Click on the
link in the description or go to
anthonypompliano.slashthat.com.
Again, click on the link in the
description and go check out TikTok for
business today.
>> What are the areas that you're actively
avoiding? We talk a lot about where
you're putting capital. Is there any
areas that you see maybe people talking
about that you're more nervous about?
>> I I still have no interest in in SaaS
seat-based software. So, you know, a lot
of people are trying to uh
pick bottoms in in that. Um aside from
that, I
I think you're going to get a lot of
sectors that are S&P 500 related. The
things that I mentioned, um
like I think between now and the end of
the year at these levels, regardless of
whether Micron sells off another 20%.
I I don't see how the memory trade
the earnings don't grow and how the S&P
doesn't go higher. So, that's one of the
things when people get worried about
things, they extrapolate a fall in a
certain stock market to something else.
So, you've heard a lot of people talk
about the debt side. Oh, this is
unbelievable. The debt's going to go.
And I want to make people feel very,
very comfortable about this. Um one of
the reasons I care so much about crypto
is because of the budget deficit. We
still have a deficit of 5 to 6%. So
again, the government is spending 5 to
6% a year more than they're getting in
receipts.
The printing press is still happening.
Meaning, this is good for nominal GDP.
At the same time, the government is in a
race against China. So, they're going to
make sure this AI trade works. They're
going to do whatever is necessary. If
the funding markets
If we see long-term rates go higher,
they got to do something because they
can't lose to China on this. And China
just gives money and opens up things in
a very different way. So, I'm very
fixated on the CapEx that's going to
happen.
AI is going to continue to accelerate.
The companies that people are worried
about the hyperscalers, their debt to
equity is It's nothing. Um so, unless
their stock price falls violently, they
have tons of ability to raise capital.
They have $2 trillion of RPOs still
sitting there. And again, so people
understand, I've never understood over
the next 2 years, if they took debt for
all of the CapEx, we're talking around
$2 trillion.
Well, there's $2 trillion between
Amazon, Microsoft, Google, and Oracle
contracted for the compute.
So again, we already have demand for
this stuff. And these guys are going to
have money to go through. So, I'm not
worried about the debt. I'm not worried
about that. So, I think people should be
focused on the areas that are going to
have a beta associated with them. And
I'm going to stick with AI
infrastructure.
All the names that I've mentioned, plus
the crypto side. So, I'm more focused on
the beta. But if you want to just go by
the S&P, I think you're going to get
great returns in the S&P for at least
the next couple of years as well.
>> What about the Nasdaq?
>> The Nasdaq has um
a beta side associated with I think is
is is good. You can you know, if you're
going to buy S&P, I think you're
generally going to get more on there.
The area on on uh
on the Nasdaq that I'm most interested
in is is probably biotech at this point.
Um
the good thing about the Nasdaq
it is
obviously heavily weighted towards the
Mag 7, which is a negative, but the
reason that it still has outperformed is
cuz it's not a pure cap weighted side,
so you're not overly weighted towards it
in there. And I think there are a lot of
areas within side the Nasdaq which will
do well, but I I I'm not sure they're
going to be able to outperform the S&P
in in a in a big way. I got to ask the
question which
I think was a good a good question.
There's a lot of people have talked
about the fact that this won't end until
we have a true bubble.
Um and they talk about it like the
dot-com bubble where Cisco's trading at
a 100 PE and that we're still in the
early stages. And I want to I want to
the people who are bullish, I want to
take them a different direction on this
cuz when I was asked the question, what
do I think on it? And I said number one,
demographics are completely different
than the dot-com bubble. Um the money
being made, you know, with the baby
boomers in this, they were still
working, they were still taking risk.
Now they're passive investments, they've
got advisers, they're playing on the
golf course, they're not sitting out
there gambling. Plus they've made so
much money, they're not trying to make
money the same way. There's obviously
active traders that are doing it, that's
fine. But then the other element that to
me is very different
and I think that's something people have
to get involved in, it gets back to this
concept that if in three years we have
AGI, at some point the stock market is
going to start saying,
"Hey uh
all businesses are going to be
disrupted."
I I don't think people realize what that
means. One of the reasons that oil
stocks basically really never go higher
in a major way and see multiple
expansion
is because it's dependent on the price
of oil. So if oil stays at $60 forever,
or if natural gas stays at $3 forever,
how is how's a company that generates
their revenues based on the underlying
asset moving actually going to get
there? Well, I think if tokens are
commoditized to zero, they don't hurt
the model companies necessarily, but I
think what they do do is they make it
easier for AI native people to compete
with all public companies because the
inability for public companies to
embrace AI
and and and make it work is going to be
much more challenging. So I only bring
that up. I think the market is going to
go through multiple compression. So I
think earnings are going to be great. I
think the S&P is going to grow
less than earnings like we've seen so
far this year, and I think that's going
to be a trend at some point in the next
3 years. I actually believe that
multiple compression story will become a
much bigger story.
>> Yeah, it's um
it's going to be fascinating, I think,
to watch this play out because
part of what you mentioned earlier, I
think, is underrated. I see a lot of
people trying to pick bottoms in SaaS
software.
And I think that you have held steady on
a view that AI is going to have a
significant impact on those businesses,
and it's more of a structural change
than a than kind of a sell-off that is
somewhat temporary. Um
and it does feel like AI now, like I
don't hear anyone saying AI is not going
to be valuable, or AI doesn't work,
right? You know, 3 years ago I heard a
lot of like, "Oh, I talked to the the
chatbot, and it was stupid. It you know,
it lied to me." type stuff, right? That
that conversation's gone. Now what I
hear a lot is like, "Who are the winners
going to be? How big can can the winners
be? How profitable can they be? What's
the impact of Chinese open source, you
know, like we're in the nuance now. And
so I take that as everyone is convinced
this is real.
Um, but I think that the one area,
[snorts] um, I still, but and I
did some of the math, uh, with Sylvia
this week, um, a very large portion of
my portfolio is exposed to physical AI
and robotics.
And it just feels like, you know, the
software side of AI has now we've gotten
so into the weeds because everyone is
looking there that the next big, you
know, kind of move, um, of capital in
within the AI trade will be that, uh,
that robotics hopefully, you know, that
at least that's what I'm betting on. Um,
do you have any exposure there? Are you
thinking at all about that the robotics
stuff?
>> So, first of all, um,
in this past
weekend's video,
uh, I I put up a chart and I got I got a
lot of good responses from people on it,
which was
and I don't think you and I have talked
about this.
When people, um, want to compare the AI
situation,
yes, the dot com bubble would come up a
lot, but the other thing that comes up
that I think it's both more recent, but
I think people are thinking about it the
right way is they bring up fracking and
what happened to all of those companies.
Now, the reason I bring it up here,
oil demand
at the end of the day is driven by
people.
And that's why it grows with nominal
GDP. So, it's a function of how many
more people are on the planet, how much
money do those people have to spend? Are
they using more energy? Like, that's
pretty much what drives the majority of
energy price and that's why if you ask
any oil person, so how much does oil
demand go up a year?
Well, what's nominal GDP? Nominal GDP is
the answer.
The problem with that is eventually with
fracking, technology made the supply
side go exponential. It actually
outpaced what happened with the demand
side. So, if the demand side stays
linear and all of a sudden we get a
technology that changes the supply side,
well, then we end up in a situation
we're in, which is no matter what seems
to happen with oil, it ends up going
back down.
And we probably don't know,
like with Hormuz, how much was shifted
to natural gas. We have endless natural
gas. What what All of these different
things have clearly changed. The problem
in what you're bringing up and the
reason I'm so focused on the
infrastructure side,
we haven't reached a point yet where we
can change the supply side of what's
necessary for this build out, because we
haven't been focused on it. That's why I
say Micron was the same price in 2017.
You know what companies don't do when
their stock price doesn't rise for 7
years? They don't build new capacity.
They don't have it. So, that's why I'm
convinced that on the memory side, when
you haven't built the capacity for any
of this stuff, it's not there. For
robotics, it's the same thing. So, you
have exponential demand for tokens.
Tokens are driven by computers. They're
driven by digital employees. They have
nothing to do with human beings. The
reason they're going parabolic is
because you just put your computer on
overnight and you say, "Okay, do this
job for the rest of the day." What
you're doing at Silvia, if you go
through your token usage, it's not just
the cost that's going higher, your usage
is going higher, too. As you grow more
people, as you guys build more systems,
as you have more agents, it'll just use
more and more tokens. It never goes
down. And so, until we get the supply
side to move up on an exponential to
match off the exponential demand, this
is something we haven't seen before and
this is why whenever I say it, I'm like,
"Guys, you're missing the point." Like
when consumer agents come, we're going
to need a lot more tokens. When
humanoids come, we need a lot more
tokens. When FSD comes, we need a lot
more tokens. So, the way I'm playing the
robotic side right now is the AI
structure trade. It's a semiconductor
trade. What is Elon Musk doing for the
robotics trade? He's building Terafab
because we don't have enough chips. So
eventually, and I'm sure I will start
buying some of these robotics things
because I do think the next trade is
embodied AI because, like you said with
software, I don't want to fight this
battle with software names. It's going
to continually be an issue.
>> I I completely agree.
I appreciate your time today. The
audience loves hearing from you. We'll
do it again next week.
>> All right, bud. Have a good one.